James A. Baker III Papers, 1957-2011 (bulk 1972-1992): Finding Aid MC197
Public Policy Papers
- Series 11: Speeches and Interviews, 1952-1995; 29 boxes
  - Subseries 11E. Secretary of State, 1989-1992; 15 boxes
    - Remarks with Russia First Deputy Prime Minister Gaydar Prior to Meeting (Department of State), 1992 April 28; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 27)
    - Remarks with Israel Foreign Minister Levy Prior to Meeting (Department of State), 1992 April 28; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 28)
    - Remarks at Luncheon for Federal Republic of Germany President and Mrs. Von Weizsaecker (Department of State), 1992 April 29; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 29)
    - Testimony Before House Foreign Affairs Committee, 1992 April 30; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 30)
    - Remarks at Foreign Service Day Luncheon, 1992 May 1; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 31)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Visit of Ukraine President and Mrs. Krachuk, 1992 May 5-1992 May 7; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 32)
    - Remarks at Swearing-In Ceremony for Edward Perkins, 1992 May 7; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Commencement Address at College of William and Mary (Williamsburg, VA), 1992 May 10; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Visit of Chile President, 1992 May 14; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Travel to London, Lisbon and Tbilisi, 1992 May 22-1992 May 26; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Visit of Russia Foreign Minister Kozyrev (Department of State), 1992 June 8-1992 June 9; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Travel to London, 1992 June 11-1992 June 13; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Visit of Russia President and Mrs. Yeltsin (White House), 1992 June 15-1992 June 18; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Remarks Prior to Meeting with Uganda President Museveni (Department of State), 1992 June 18; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Remarks at Swearing-In Ceremony for Peter Teeley, 1992 June 18; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - PBS "MacNeil-Lehrer Newshour" Interview, 1992 June 18; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 10)
    - CNN "Newsmaker Saturday" Interview, 1992 June 20; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 11)
    - ABC "This Week With David Brinkley" Interview, 1992 June 21; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 12)
    - Testimony Before Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1992 June 23; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 13)
    - Remarks at Ceremony Conferring Rank of Career Ambassador Hank Cohen, 1992 June 24; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 14)
    - Address to World Affairs Council of Boston, 1992 June 25; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 15)
    - Remarks Prior to Meeting with Zaire Archbishop Pasinya (Department of State), 1992 June 26; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 16)
    - Remarks at 50 Year Service Award Ceremony for Richard Curl, 1992 June 29; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 17)
    - Remarks with Federal Republic of Germany Foreign Minister Kinkel Prior to Meeting, 1992 June 30; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 18)
    - White House Press Conference, 1992 July 1; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 19)
    - Remarks Following Meeting with Mozambique President Chissano (Department of State), 1992 July 2; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 20)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Travel with President Bush to Warsaw, Munich and Helsinki, 1992 July 4-1992 July 10; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 21)
    - Remarks with Nambia Prime Minister Geingob Prior to Meeting (Department of State), 1992 July 13; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 22)
    - Remarks in Conjunction with Travel to Amman, Jerusalem, Damascus, Cairo, Jabla, Damascus, Zahleh, Jeddah, Manila, 1992 July 18-1992 July 26; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 23)
    - Remarks at Swearing-In Ceremony for Reginald Bartholomew, 1992 July 29; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 24)
    - Remarks with J. Talabani Prior to Meeting with Iraqi Opposition Delegation (Department of State), 1992 July 29; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 25)
    - Remarks Upon Resignation as Secretary of State, 1992 August 13; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 26)
    - Remarks at Christening of the Port Royal (Pascagoula, Mississippi), 1992 December 5; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 27)
    - Schedule of Speeches, Statements, Remarks, Toasts, Interviews and Press Conferences by Baker, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 28)
  - Subseries 11F. Miscellaneous Speech Material, 1981-1995; 2 boxes
    The Miscellaneous Speech Material includes several folders of undated speech material, as well as two folders of jokes and other humorous anecdotes for use in various speeches.
    - Joke/Humor Material, 1981-1995; 2 folders (Box 170, Folder 29-30)
    - Master Speech, undated; 2 folders (Box 171, Folder 1-2)
    - Toast to Arnaud de Borchgrave, undated; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - Speech delivered at memorial of George Pratt Shultz, 2021 October 7; 1 folder (Box 330)
- Series 12: The Politics of Diplomacy, 1989-1995; 27 boxes; 2 items
  The Politics of Diplomacy series includes drafts, notes, interview transcripts and other files related to the writing of Baker's first book, The Politics of Diplomacy. The book details Baker's involvement in world events during his tenure as Secretary of State, 1989-1992; specific events include the fall of the Berlin Wall, the end of the Cold War and the breakup of the Soviet Union, the end of apartheid in South Africa, and the crisis in Bosnia. There are original materials within this series that are not found elsewhere, and they often correlate with the chapters in Baker's memoirs.
  The series is divided into two subseries: Background and Research Material and Chapter Files.
  Interview transcripts in Series 12: The Politics of Diplomacy are closed unless permission, specific to each transcript, is granted by Secretary Baker as well as the person who gave the interview. These transcripts are located in Boxes 172-173. Please contact the library for additional details.
  - Subseries 12A. Background and Research Materials, 1989-1995; 9 boxes
    The Background and Research Material subseries comprises background material used in the writing of The Politics of Diplomacy. Materials in the subseries consist of calendars and chronologies, interview transcripts, and various other notes, memos, and documents.
    Of special note are the interview transcripts of interviews of Baker and his high level staff, such as Dennis Ross and Bob Zoellick, on the subject of major foreign policy events. Most interviews were conducted by Baker's coauthor Tom DeFrank; they touch on most major events and issues dealt with in the book. Also of interest are the Meetings, Moments, and Controversies files, which include Baker's notes from many notable occasions.
    A small amount of the material in this subseries, such as copies of State Department materials, may duplicate that found in other portions of the collection.
    Interview transcripts in Series 12: The Politics of Diplomacy are closed unless permission, specific to each transcript, is granted by Secretary Baker and the person who gave the interview. These transcripts are located in Boxes 172-173. Please contact the library for additional details.
    - General Files, 1989-1995; 6 boxes
      - Background, 1992-1993; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 4)
      - Calendars, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 5)
      - Carpendale, Andrew, 1989-1995; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 6)
      - Chronologies, 1989-1992; 2 boxes
        - Arab-Israeli Peace Process, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 7)
        - Baker, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 8)
        - Foreign Relations,1989-1992, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 172, Folder 1-2)
      - DeFrank, Tom, 1993-1995; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 3)
      - Document Requests, 1992-1994; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 4)
      - Interview Transcripts, 1993-1994; 2 boxes
        - Baker, James A., 1993-1994; 3 folders (Box 172, Folder 5-7)
          Permission from Secretary Baker is required to access.
        - Burns, Bill, 1993; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 1)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Bill Burns is required to access.
        - Djerejian, Edward, 1993; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 2)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Edward Djerejian is required to access.
        - Graves, Howard, 1993; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 3)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Howard Graves is required to access.
        - Kimmitt, Bob, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 4)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Bob Kimmitt is required to access.
        - Kurtzer, Dan, 1994 (incomplete), 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 5)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Dan Kurtzer is required to access.
        - Mullins, Janet, 1993; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 6)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Janet Mullins is required to access.
        - Ross, Dennis, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 7)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Dennis Ross is required to access.
        - Zoellick, Bob, 1993; 1 folder (Box 331, Folder 8)
          Permission from Secretary Baker and Bob Zoellick is required to access.
      - Interviews, Miscellaneous Notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 173, Folder 1-2)
      - Interviews, Miscellaneous Notes, undated (continued) (1 Folder), 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - Key Points Memos, 1993; 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 2)
      - Meeting Agendas, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 3)
      - Notes, Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 4)
      - Nyren, Neil, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 5)
      - Process/Timeline Memos, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 6)
      - Promotional Materials, 1995 (1 Folder), 1 folder (Box 174, Folder 7)
      - Promotional Materials, 1995 (continued), 2 folders (Box 175, Folder 1-2)
      - Prospectus and Chapter Outline, 1992-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - Reading, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 4)
      - Section and Chapter Headings, 1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 5)
      - Strategy and Process, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1992-1995; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - Andrew Carpendale Files, 1989-1995; 4 boxes
      - Anecdotes, undated; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 8)
      - Book Group, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 9)
      - Chapter Headings, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 10)
      - Contacts and Sources, 1989-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 11)
      - Declassification, 1992-1994; 1 box
        - Approvals, 1992; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 12)
        - Requests, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 13)
      - Document Requests, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 175, Folder 14)
      - Key Questions, 1991-1994; 1 box
        - General, undated; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 1)
        - End of Cold War, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 2)
        - Gulf War, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 3)
        - Other Topics, 1993; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 4)
      - Maps and Photographs, Miscellaneous, 1993; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 5)
      - Meetings, James A. Baker, 1993; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 6)
      - Meetings, Moments, and Controversies Files (chronological), 1989-1992; 1 box
        - NATO Ministerial on Comprehensive Concept, 1989; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 7)
        - "70% Approval Rating" and the Nostalgia for the Cold War, 1989; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 8)
        - Malta Summit, 1989; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 9)
        - Invasion of Panama, 1989; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 10)
        - Margin of Open Skies Conference, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 11)
        - Mikhail Gorbachev in Moscow, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 12)
        - Trip to Prague, Moscow, Sofia, Bucharest, and Ottawa, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 13)
        - "Nine Assurances" on German Unification, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 14)
        - Irkutsk Ministerial with Eduard Shevardnadze, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 15)
        - Gorbachev and Shevardnadze in Moscow, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 16)
        - U.N. Security Council Session Authorizing Force, 1990; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 17)
        - Taif Speech, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 18)
        - Lunch with President Bush on the Day the War Began, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 19)
        - Joint Statement with Bessmertnykh, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 20)
        - Meeting with War Cabinet, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 21)
        - Meeting with Yugoslav Leaders, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 22)
        - Visit to Gobi Desert, Mongolia, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 23)
        - Departure from State Department, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 24)
        - Gorbachev and Yeltsin, Post-coup Meetings in Moscow, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 25)
        - Coup and Post-coup Meetings with Bush, Cheney, Scowcroft, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 26)
        - Madrid Middle East Peace Conference, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 27)
        - Meetings with Gorbachev, Shevardnadze, and Yeltsin, 1991; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 28)
        - Boris Yeltsin in Moscow, 1992; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 29)
        - Yeltsin Washington Summit, 1992; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 30)
        - Oval Office Meeting with President Yeltsin to Finish START II, 1992; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 31)
        - Oval Office Meeting with Bush, Powell, Cheney, Scowcroft, on Bosnia, 1992; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 32)
        - Top Ten Meetings, Moments, Mistakes/Controversies, undated; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 33)
      - Memoirs, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 34)
      - Peace Process Secondary Literature, 1993; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 35)
      - Planning/Status Reports, 1994; 1 folder (Box 176, Folder 36)
      - Publisher/Marketing, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 177, Folder 1)
      - Putnam's Sons, 1994; 2 folders (Box 177, Folder 2-3)
      - Reclama File, undated; 1 folder (Box 177, Folder 4)
      - Research Sources, 1993; 1 folder (Box 177, Folder 5)
      - State Department, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 177, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous Book Materials, 1993-1995; 4 folders (Box 177, Folder 7-10)
      - Miscellaneous Book Materials, 1993-1995; 2 folders (Box 178, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries 12B. Chapter Files, 1989-1995; 19 boxes; 2 items
    The Chapter Files subseries contains multiple drafts of each chapter, including the Preface and Acknowledgements, of The Politics of Diplomacy, as well as some memos, notes, or background material. Later drafts and proofs of the full book can be found at the end of the subseries.
    Several drafts of a single chapter may include editing by Baker, Andrew Carpendale, Tom DeFrank, and occasionally others such as Bob Zoellick or Margaret Tutwiler. Significant changes in content and tone may be observed through various iterations of a chapter.
    The subseries is arranged by chapter number.
    - Preface and Acknowledgement, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 178, Folder 3)
      - Baker Files, 1995; 2 folders (Box 178, Folder 4-5)
    - Chapter 1: The Day the Cold War Ended, 1993-1994; 2 boxes
      - General Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 178, Folder 6-7)
      - Baker Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 179, Folder 1-2)
    - Chapter 2: Three Decades of Friendship, 1993-1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 179, Folder 3-4)
      - Baker Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 179, Folder 5-6)
    - Chapter 3: The World on the Eve of a Revolution, 1993-1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 4: Rebuilding Bipartisanship: Lancing the Central American Boil, 1989-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 180, Folder 2-3)
      - Baker Files, 1989-1995; 2 folders (Box 180, Folder 4-5)
    - Chapter Five: The Soviet Union: Gorbachev, Shevardnadze, and the "New Thinking", 1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 181, Folder 1-2)
    - Chapter Six: A "Europe Whole and Free", 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - Chapter Seven: China: A Great Leap Backward, 1989-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 181, Folder 4)
      - Baker Files, 1989-1995; 2 folders (Box 181, Folder 5-6)
    - Chapter Eight: The Middle East: First Encounters with the Quagmire, 1990-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 182, Folder 1-2)
      - Baker Files, 1990-1995; 2 folders (Box 182, Folder 3-4)
    - Chapter Nine: The Spirit of Jackson Hole, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 182, Folder 5-6)
    - Chapter 10: The Fall of the Wall, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 11: Panama: The Day of the Dictator Is Over, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 183, Folder 2)
      - Baker Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 183, Folder 3-4)
    - Chapter 12: The Arithmetic of Unification, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 2 folders (Box 184, Folder 1-2)
    - Chapter 13: Africa: The End of Apartheid, 1989-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 184, Folder 3)
      - Baker Files, 1989-1995; 2 folders (Box 184, Folder 4-5)
    - Chapter 14: Spring of Tumult: German Unification, Lithuanian Independence, and Soviet Upheaval, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 2 folders (Box 184, Folder 6-7)
    - Chapter 15: Prelude to an Invasion, 1989-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 185, Folder 1-2)
      - Baker Files, 1989-1995; 4 folders (Box 185, Folder 3-6)
    - Chapter 16: Building the Coalition, 1993-1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 186, Folder 1-2)
      - Baker Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 186, Folder 3-4)
    - Chapter 17: All Necessary Means, 1994-1995; 2 boxes
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 186, Folder 5-6)
      - Baker Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 187, Folder 1-2)
    - Chapter 18: Forging Consensus at Home, 1993-1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 187, Folder 3)
      - Baker Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 187, Folder 4-5)
    - Chapter 19: The Last, Best Chance for Peace, 1991-1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 188, Folder 1-2)
      - Baker Files, 1991-1994; 2 folders (Box 188, Folder 3-4)
    - Chapter 20: The Shield Becomes a Sword, 1993-1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 189, Folder 1-2)
      - Baker Files, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 21: Passing the Brink, 1994; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 4)
      - Baker Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 22: Gorbachev's Gambit, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 6)
      - Baker Files, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 23: A Postwar Vision for the Mideast, 1994; 2 boxes
      - General Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 189, Folder 8-9)
      - Baker Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 24: Saddam Stays in Power, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 190, Folder 2-3)
      - Baker Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 25: Prelude to a Mideast Conference: The Dead Cat on the Doorstep, 1994-1995; 2 boxes
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 190, Folder 5-6)
      - General Files (continued), 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 191, Folder 1)
      - Baker Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 191, Folder 2-3)
    - Chapter 26: From Berlin to the Balkans, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 27: Breakthrough for Peace, 1994-1995; 2 boxes
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 191, Folder 5-6)
      - Baker Files, 1994; 3 folders (Box 192, Folder 1-3)
    - Chapter 28: The Empire Shaken, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 192, Folder 4-5)
    - Chapter 29: Settlements, Loan Guarantees, and the Politics of Peace, 1994-1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1994; 1 folder (Box 193, Folder 1)
      - Baker Files, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 193, Folder 2-3)
    - Chapter 30: Into the Dustbin: With a Whimper, Not a Bang, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 2 folders (Box 193, Folder 4-5)
    - Chapter 31: Entering a New Era, 1991-1995; 2 boxes
      - General Files, 1995 (1 Folder), 1 folder (Box 193, Folder 6)
      - General Files, 1995 (continued) (1 Folder), 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 1)
      - Baker Files, 1991-1995; 3 folders (Box 194, Folder 2-4)
    - Chapter 32: Supporting Freedom in the New Independent States, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 33: "Humanitarian Nightmare" in Bosnia, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 34: From Cold War to Democratic Peace, 1995; 1 box
      - General Files, 1995; 1 folder (Box 195, Folder 1)
    - Deleted Chapter: International Economics, 1995; 1 folder (Box 195, Folder 2)
    - Galley Proofs, 1995; 3 folders (Box 195, Folder 3-5)
    - Big Bad Book (full draft), 1995; 2 boxes; 2 items
      - Preface - Chapter 4, 1995; 1 folder (Box 195, Folder 6)
      - Chapter 5 - Chapter 12, 1995; 1 folder (Box 196, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 13 - Chapter 21, 1995; 1 folder (Box 196, Folder 2)
      - Chapter 22 - Chapter 29, 1995; 1 folder (Box 196, Folder 3)
      - Chapter 30 - Chapter 34, Miscellaneous, 1995; 1 folder (Box 196, Folder 4)
      - Big Bad Book (full draft), undated; 1 item
- Series 13: Scrapbooks and Memorabilia, 1980 August-1993; 62 boxes
  The Scrapbooks and Memorabilia series consists of large binders and other scrapbooks created by Baker's staff during his time as White House Chief of Staff, Secretary of the Treasury, and Secretary of State, as well as during various political campaigns. Whenever possible the material has been removed from binders and scrapbooks and rehoused for preservation purposes.
  The series is divided into two subseries, Weekly and Monthly Scrapbooks and Yearly Scrapbooks. Scrapbooks in both subseries include newspaper and magazine clippings. The Weekly and Monthly Scrapbooks consist primarily of clippings with other material, such as press conference transcripts, schedules, or White House phone records also present. The Yearly Scrapbooks are more likely to include memorabilia, such as identification badges for major events, or mementos from trips abroad. The Chief of Staff Scrapbook 1 (Box 246) includes Baker's handwritten notes from March 30, 1981, the day of the attempted assignation attempt on President Reagan.
  Researchers should note that a small number of clippings can be found within the other individual series.
  The series also contains two boxes of memorabilia, including campaign buttons from Baker's attorney general campaign, foreign versions of The Politics of Diplomacy, and miscellaneous binders and portfolios from Baker's work on presidential campaigns or his various government positions.
  The series is divided into three major groupings. Each subseries is arranged roughly chronologically.
  - Monthly and Weekly Scrapbooks, 1980 August-1993; 50 boxes
    - 1980 August-1980 November, 2 folders (Box 197, Folder 1-2)
    - 1980 September-1980 December, 2 folders (Box 197, Folder 3-4)
    - 1980 November 1-1981 February 2, 2 folders (Box 197, Folder 5-6)
    - 1981 February 2-1981 March 29 ( 2 Folders), 2 folders (Box 198, Folder 1-2)
    - 1981 March 30-1981 May 7, 2 folders (Box 198, Folder 3-4)
    - 1981 May 8-1981 June 8, 2 folders (Box 199, Folder 1-2)
    - 1981 June 8-1981 July 13, 2 folders (Box 199, Folder 3-4)
    - 1981 July 14-1981 August 31, 2 folders (Box 199, Folder 5-6)
    - 1981 September 1-1981 October 17, 2 folders (Box 200, Folder 1-2)
    - 1981 October 17-November 10, 2 folders (Box 200, Folder 3-4)
    - 1981 November 11-1981 November 30 (1 Folder), 1 folder (Box 200, Folder 5)